Guide to the Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
5488 B
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
669 linear feet.
Correspondence, Rule books, Agreements, etc.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
Subjects:
Railroads--Employees--Labor unions--United States--Sources.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted. Please contact the Kheel Center Reference Archivist for access information.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
This forms a portion of collection #5488 B. The guide to the entire collection is available here.
Series III is arranged in 54 sub-series by Union file number.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series III. PROTECTIVE LAWS
  - Sub-Series 202-0-5. Protective Laws
    - General, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 34)
      1962 May 5
  - Sub-Series 202-0. Protective Laws
    - General, 1922-1959 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Sub-Series 202-1. Protective Laws
    - Per capita tax, 1933-1959 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Per capita tax and assessments. System Boards of adjustment, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 37)
      Dec. 14, 1932.
    - System Board for per capita tax, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 38)
      Oct. 8, 1929.
    - Per capita tax, 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Sub-Series 202-2. Protective Laws
    - Tenure of office. Local protective Committee, 1931-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Tenure of office, local chairman, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Dec. 16, 1929.
  - Sub-Series 202-3. Protective Laws
    - Election of Protective Committee (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Election of Protective Committee, 1944-1947. (Box 13, Folder 4)
      1944-47..
    - Election of Protective Committee, 1939-1943 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Election of Protective Committee, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Election of Protective Committee, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      Aug. 5, 1932.
    - Election of Protective Committee, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Nov. 27, 1929.
  - Sub-Series 202-4. Protective Laws
    - Per capita tax-Erie System Board -Jan. 21, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series 202-5. Protective Laws
    - Delinquent Lodges, per capita tax-Pennsylvania System Board, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Jan. 8, 1923.
  - Sub-Series 202-6. Protective Laws
    - per capita tax-L and N System Board, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      Feb. 14, 1921.
  - Sub-Series 202-7. Protective Laws
    - per capita tax-L and N System Board, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series 202-8. Protective Laws
    - per capita tax-CB and Q System Board, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Feb. 5, 1921.
  - Sub-Series 202-9. Protective Laws
    - per capita tax-B and O System Board-Lodge No. 244, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 14)
      Feb. 7, 1921.
  - Sub-Series 202-10. Protective Laws
    - Formation of System Boards, 1931-1958 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Formation of System Boards, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      Dec. 19, 1928.
  - Sub-Series 202-11. Protective Laws
    - C and NW System Board, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 18)
      1921 March, 2
  - Sub-Series 202-12. Protective Laws
    - Election of division chairmen, 1948-1959 (Box 13, Folder 17)
      Oct. 1948-59.
    - Election of division chairmen, 1933-1948 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      1933-Sept. 1948.
    - Election of division chairmen, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Election of division chairmen, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Election of division chairmen, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Election of division chairmen (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Election of division chairmen, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 24)
      Dec. 17, 1928.
  - Sub-Series 202-13. Protective Laws
    - Consolidation of offices, 1921-1957 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Sub-Series 202-14. Protective Laws
    - Grievances, 1950-1958 (Box 13, Folder 26)
      June 1950-58.
    - Grievances, 1945-1950 (Box 13, Folder 27)
      1945-May 1950.
    - Grievances, 1935-1944 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Grievances, 1930-1934 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Grievances, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Dec. 10, 1929.
  - Sub-Series 202-15. Protective Laws
    - Proxy representation, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      1935 April 3
  - Sub-Series 202-16. Protective Laws
    - Consolidation of two or more railroads, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      1921 March, 7
  - Sub-Series 202-17. Protective Laws
    - Fort Worth and Denver City Railway System Board per capita tax, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      1921 April, 14
  - Sub-Series 202-18. Protective Laws
    - AB and A strike -Oct. 22, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 202-19. Protective Laws
    - Discussing of grievances with officials, 1936-1954 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Handling of grievance by local protective Committee, 1924 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Feb. 20, 1924.
  - Sub-Series 202-20. Protective Laws
    - Election of officers, 1922-1957 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series 202-21. Protective Laws
    - AB and A strike, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      1982 March, 25
  - Sub-Series 202-23. Protective Laws
    - Tenure of offices, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Aug. 28, 1934.
    - Tenure of office-System Board officers, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Feb. 23, 1926.
  - Sub-Series 202-24. Protective Laws
    - Election of local chairmen, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      Sept. 6, 1929.
    - Election chairmen local Protective Committee, 1952-1959 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Election chairmen local Protective Committee, 1949-1951 (Box 14, Folder 15)
      March 18, 1949-51.
    - Election chairmen local Protective Committee, 1930-1949 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      1930-March 17, 1949.
  - Sub-Series 202-26. Protective Laws
    - Eligibility of System Board officers and members -1931-58 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Qualification of Lodge officers, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Sub-Series 202-27. Protective Laws
    - Eligibility to Membership-Protective Committee, 1951-1959 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      Oct. 1951-59.
    - Eligibility to Membership-Protective Committee, 1956-1959 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Eligibility to Membership-Protective Committee, 1948-1951 (Box 14, Folder 21)
      1948-Sept. 1951.
    - Eligibility to Membership-Protective Committee, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Eligibility to Membership-Protective Committee, 1944-1946 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Eligibility to Membership-Protective Committee, 1941-1943 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Eligibility to Membership-Protective Committee, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Eligibility of Membership of the Protective Committee, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 26)
      Oct. 14, 1931.
  - Sub-Series 202-29. Protective Laws
    - Disbursements from the Protective fund, 1924 (Box 14, Folder 27)
      Jan. 24, 1924.
  - Sub-Series 202-30. Protective Laws
    - Right of regularly elected division chairmen to sit as a member of the Board of adjustment, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 28)
      1929 March 6
  - Sub-Series 202-31. Protective Laws
    - Appeal from decision of general chairmen, 1924-1956 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Sub-Series 202-32. Protective Laws
    - Duties and powers of general chairmen and other officers or System Boards of adjustment, 1924-1957 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Sub-Series 202-33. Protective Laws
    - Recall of System Board officers, 1925-1959 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series 202-34. Protective Laws
    - Section 31, Article 1-Supervision Vice Grand Presidents, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Oct. 20, 1925.
  - Sub-Series 202-35. Protective Laws
    - Eligibility-System Board members, 1950-1956 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Series 202-36. Protective Laws
    - System Board Bylaws, 1956-1958 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Nov. 1956-58.
    - System Board Bylaws, 1954-1956 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      May 1954-Oct. 1956.
    - System Board Bylaws, 1952-1954 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      May 1952-April 1954.
    - System Board Bylaws, 1951-1952 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Oct. 1951-April 1952.
    - System Board Bylaws, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      June 15, 1951-Sept. 1951.
    - System Board Bylaws, 1949-1951 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      1949-June 14, 1951.
    - System Board Bylaws, 1928-1948 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series 202-37. Protective Laws
    - Audit of System Board records, 1929-1957 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 202-38. Protective Laws
    - Compensation-Members Protective Committee, 1929-1951 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series 202-39. Protective Laws
    - Special assessments by System Boards, 1929-1959 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Sub-Series 202-41. Protective Laws
    - When does a local chairman assume office, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      1930 January 4
  - Sub-Series 202-42. Protective Laws
    - Instructions to System Board members, 1929-1957 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series 202-43. Protective Laws
    - Disbursement of System Board funds, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Sub-Series 202-44. Protective Laws
    - Division Protective Committee, 1944-1958 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Division Protective Committee, 1936-1943 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Division Protective Committees, 1930-1934 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Sub-Series 202-45. Protective Laws
    - Delinquent in payment of dues, 1930-1954 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Sub-Series 202-46. Protective Laws
    - The right of System Board officers to perform official duties while under charges, 1932-1957 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Sub-Series 202-47. Protective Laws
    - Requesting Lodges to furnish copy of Lodge audits to System Boards of adjustment (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Sub-Series 202-48. Protective Laws
    - Duties of local Protective Committee, 1933-1956 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Sub-Series 202-49. Protective Laws
    - Qualifications of division chairmen -1934-51 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Sub-Series 202-50. Protective Laws
    - Compensation of System Board officers, 1934-1954 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Sub-Series 202-51. Protective Laws
    - Duties of Board of trustees, 1934-1956 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Sub-Series 202-52. Protective Laws
    - Strike benefits, 1945-1957 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Sub-Series 202-53. Protective Laws
    - Boards of adjustment duties, etc., 1948-1957 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Sub-Series 202-54. Protective Laws
    - Authorizing spreading of strike ballots-failure to adjust grievances, 1948-1958 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Sub-Series 202-56. Protective Laws
    - Duties of division chairman, 1952-1956 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Sub-Series 202-55. Protective Laws
    - Certifications-General chairmen, 1951-1953. (Box 15, Folder 31)
      1951-53..